Muhammad Jaelani Abdul Azis

Address: West Java, Bekasi | No Telp: +62 85893270940 | Email: muhammadaziz0354@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/muhammadaziz06/ | https://muhammadaziz06.github.io/



PROFILE

Hello everyone, I am an Information Systems graduate from UIN Syarif Hidayatullah Jakarta with a GPA of 3.66. I have an interest in technology. That is what led me to the world of technology, I have experience working as a System Analyst, IT Governance, IT Implementer, and IT Application Support. I have expertise in website development, IT governance, system analysis, database, IT implementation and project management. I have a good ability to work and adapt easily to new people and circumstances, and also I can work under pressure, individual and team work, and I like to learn new things.

EDUCATION

Universitas Islam Negeri Syarif Hidayatullah Jakarta

Information Systems | GPA 3.66

• Bachelor's degree with a major in Information Systems and a GPA of 3.66/4.

Jakarta, Indonesia Jul 2018 – Jun 2023

SMA PGRI 1 Bekasi

Natural Science

Bekasi, Indonesia Jun 2015 – Jun 2018

• When I was in school, I won many competitions such as chess competitions, choir competitions, abang & mpok competitions, tandu darurat competitions and became vice president of PMR SMA PGRI 1 Bekasi.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Application Support | Contract

Oct 2023 - Now

PT Bosnet Distribution Indonesia By Telkom Indonesia – Jakarta, Indonesia

- Troubleshoot problems related to the system, including handling errors when running the system and managing the database.
- Provide direction and solutions to system problems effectively and efficiently to users.
- Clean up all data in the database based on requests from clients.
- Perform CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) operations on the database.
- Monitor the entire system to keep it running properly.
- Coordinate with developers if there are bugs in the system, perform manual testing to ensure the application is running properly, and deploy the application to the production server.

IT Implementer | Contract

Sep 2023 - Oct 2023

PT Bosnet Distribution Indonesia By Telkom Indonesia – Jakarta, Indonesia

- Successfully implemented BOSNET Distribution software to clients
- Transfer knowledge/training on business processes and applications to customers.
- Set up, configure, and test the application to ensure it runs properly.
- Perform live preparation, such as: data transfer, application setup, and get sign off balance
- Monitoring the implementation process: Supervise user data entry, provide direction and solutions to problems or errors.

IT Governance | Internship

Des 2022 - Mar 2023

Diskominfostandi of Bekasi City - Bekasi, Indonesia

 Analyzing and evaluating information technology governance at the Bekasi City Communication and Informatics Office using the COBIT 2019 framework.

System Analyst | Internship

Jul 2022 – Jan 2023

Berijalan Technocenter Astra Credit Company - Yogyakarta, Indonesia

- Lead and manage the team in creating an application given by the mentor in the company.
- Created and organized the team in sprint, timeline, story point, sprint review and sprint retrospective.
- Became the best team in project challenge, best final presentation in real project and quiz in scrum method.
- Created application overviews and technical documents (software requirements specifications) such as activity diagrams, use
 case diagrams, functional specifications, sequence diagrams, and created user interfaces or system mockups to quickly present
 to users.

Ministry of Religion Affairs of Bekasi City - Bekasi, Indonesia

- Placed in the administrative department in the field of personnel with the work of processing data input and output processes, IT support and processing several correspondence letters.
- Management of all employee data at the Ministry of Religion in the city of Bekasi.

Duta Perubahan Perilaku | Volunteer

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

Satuan Tugas Penanganan Covid – 19 Bidang Perubahan Perilaku – Jakarta, Indonesia

- Socializing and educating the public about the importance of the 5M health protocol (wash hands, wear masks, keep distance, stay away from crowds, limited mobility).
- Distributing masks and hand sanitizer, making posters, and socializing through social media.

CERTIFICATION & TRAINING

Certificate of Completion Javascript with API Certificate of Completion World of Programming Certificate of Completion MY SQL Certificate of Completion Python Certified International Specialist Data Visualization Digital Talent Scholarship Kominfo, 2022 Kecerdasan Digital ID CfDS UGM, 2022 PROGATE ID, 2020 PROGATE ID, 2020 Cybertrend Data Academy, 2019

SOFT SKILLS & HARD SKILLS

Soft Skills: Creative and Innovative, Ability to Work Under Pressure, Responsible, Time Management, Critical and Logical Thinking, Communication and Focus, Leadership, and Problem Solving.

Hard Skills: Microsoft Office, HTML & CSS, Javascript, Database, MYSQL, Python, Git, Business Analysis, Balsamiq Wirefrimes, Canva, IT Support, Figma, Data Analyst and Visualization, and COBIT 2019.

ADDITIONAL

Portfolio

• https://muhammadaziz06.github.io/

Languages

Indonesian : Native proficiencyEnglish : Basic Proficiency